Santiago Bustamante Garcia

+57 (300) 729 6896 busta117@gmail.com skype: sbusta117 www.santiagobustamante.info

SUMMARY

I'm an engineer who love the new technologies with several years of experience developing native iOS games and applications both in academic and professional projects. I have experience developing REST APIs for communicate the client and the server. I have participated in multiple projects which gave me great experience personally and professionally working both my myself and in a team.

EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer, KOGI Mobile

Medellín, Antioquia — jun 2013 - Current

I'm a member of the iOS developers team, in this job i'm in charge of VarCity app(https://itun.es/i6Fk2vj) and another app currently on development. Also i participate in the development of Ground Miles by Bupa (https://itun.es/i6FV2Q6), UNE MAS (https://itun.es/i6Fp5hj), phase 2 of PureGym app (https://itun.es/i6Fz6yV), iOS app for TP Orthodontics (http://www.tportho.com/ still on development), and iOS version of Beats Medical app (http://www.beatsmedical.com/ still on development)

iOS Developer, GARA Entertainment

Medellín, Antioquia — dec 2011 - jun 2013

I developed several games using Objective-C and frameworks such as cocos2D, box2D and Unity. I developed native iOS apps and theirs backend in php and WCF. In this job I was in charge of the development of Oh My Nuts!

Game(https://itun.es/i6Fk25f), their free version (https://itun.es/i6F27C2) and two other games that are not in the AppStore yet, GoBo(http://youtu.be/nGUnDZoJ_NE) and StreetRep (http://youtu.be/LWIAKDe26OM); also i developed the ipad version for a colombian retail named ÉXITO (https://itun.es/i6Fk3H9)

iOS Developer, Doctus LTDA

Medellín, Antioquia — jun 2011 - dec 2011

I developed some frameworks for use in house, also started the development of several iOS games.

iOS Developer, Freelance

I developed some iOS native apps for external clients, some of these applications still alive in the AppStore with the following links:

<u>https://itun.es/i6FV2yH</u> (internet radio station, Medellin Hip Hop)
<u>https://itun.es/i6Fk3H3</u> (sushi restaurant in Medellin-Colombia,
Sushi Market)

https://itun.es/i6Fk25x (events list for ANDI)

social network using GPS called MNU, this app is not alive

TUAPP Contest 2013

I participated in the University Apps Contest powered by Cursor in Santiago de Chile, in this contest we're finalists with an application that suggests another way of tourism using quests.

EDUCATION

EAFIT University (Medellin - Colombia)

System Engineering — 2007-2013

SKILLS

- Objective-C and iOS development for iOS 4.3 and above
- Java.
- PHP.
- MySQL.
- Xcode
- Memory management and debugging for iOS apps using instruments.
- Cocos2D, Box2D and Unity frameworks for mobile game developing.
- C#
- WCF for REST API
- Adobe products (photoshop, illustrator, flash, premiere)